Hello, everyone, welcome back to today's another new tutorial topic.
So, to do let's explore the minimum and the maximum function in the post-field SQL, okay.
And here, just to use to find the minimum and the maximum values in the set of data, okay.
So, first of all, simply explain for the minimum and the maximum function in the post-field SQL.
It's a powerful tool for finding the smallest and the largest value in the column set of data.
And now, they are commonly used in various analytical and the reporting test, okay.
So, first of all, here finding the minimum value.
So, now, let's get started. So, here, first of all, I'm going to start with the list, okay.
And there, I can use for the minimum.
So, now, let's jump and perfectly use and select and then different for the minimum.
And, in this inside, I can declare the summary column and then going to the next system and here,
it was in command here describing this, the employees, okay.
So, you can see here the perfectly employees and here simply using the minimum function to find
the smallest salary from the salary column of the employee table, okay.
Now, just select and execute.
You can see here the minimum salary is 30,000, okay. So, I hope you understand it.
Then, the complete and next step here, finding for the maximum salary.
You can simply use the maximum or simply use the maximum, okay.
So, the maximum salary to find the largest salary from the salary column of the employee table,
okay. So, here, select and then, and code, you can see here the maximum salary for the 60,000,
okay. So, you can see here this operation is perfectly successful and the post grade,
SQL will return the minimum salary as the result, okay.
So, here, this is perfectly explored for the two examples, okay.
Next step here, I create both for the maximum and the minimum value, okay.
So, here it stands for first of all here, I can use the select and type the minimum and
use the instant defined for the salary column and there I use for then open and here,
it is for the both minimum and the maximum function to find the smallest and the largest
salaries from the salary column of the employee table, okay.
So, you can see here this data query and now just here select and then
I can just execute and you can see here perfectly face the print, the smallest salary for the
30,000 and the highest salary for the 60,000, okay. And this operation is successful and the post
grade, SQL will return both the minimum and the maximum salaries as the result, okay.
So, I hope you perfectly understand this. Next, I can use for the most important part,
the minimum and the maximum value with the condition, okay.
So, in this section, I can use for simply this and now just again defined for here the
H column and also here I can define for the minimum and the maximum, okay. It's okay.
And now, 2 is for here the employee table and also here is the y plus this is a
department, okay. And this equal to so here I can use for department of the HR, okay.
So, now here the minimum maximum function find the smallest largest space and the employee table,
but only the employees in the HR department, okay. So, here I'll select and execute.
Now, you can see here the same H for the 27, 27 because the HR department got only one
department for the employee table. So, now just verify and first of all, we have to select
multiplication sign from where I choose the employee statement, okay. And now just select all and then
exist group and now here is set here this is perfect and here the all row for here the
just 27 and this the employee table information, okay. So, I hope you perfectly understand and
here I can perfectly overview this in the minimum maximum function in post space school you
some practical example, okay. So, I hope you perfectly understand the session. So, thank you for
Thank you for watching and happy coding.